Andrey Marchenko

Senior full-stack developer

Location: Berlin, Germany E-Mail: anvmarchenko@gmail.com

Full-stack developer with 6 years of experience both in enterprise and startup areas. I enjoy solving challenging tasks and creating great products making peoples' life better. I have successful experience performing full cycle of project development from requirements to production setup.

My favourite tools to date are Ruby on Rails for backend, react/redux for frontend, docker and ansible for devops. Also I have experience with Angularjs, jQuery, vanilla JS on frontend and Java (Spring framework) on backend. Currently I learn Elixir language and Phoenix framework and feel really excited about it.

Besides my main work I develop my side project (Hamster Travel) in which my passions for travel and creation are combined.

Keywords

- Ruby on Rails (RSpec, Capybara), linting (rubocop)
- Elixir/Phoenix
- Javascript, ES6, eslint, Angularjs, React, HTML5, CSS3
- Java (Spring Boot, Spring Data)
- Postgresql, Mongodb
- Elasticsearch
- Docker, Ansible
- Logging: ELK stack, rollbar
- Monitoring: Datadog, New Relic
- Vagrant
- Git

Languages

- Russian (native)
- English (full working proficiency)
- German (limited working proficiency)

Work experience

FinReach, Senior full-stack developer January 2015 - present

As one of the first developers in the company performed full cycle of development for several company's internal and external products. The most notable project is automated bank account switch kit, which is one of the most innovative and modern products in banking area in Germany.

• Full-stack development of several products using Ruby on Rails, Angularjs and Mongodb

- Implemented automated unit and integration testing for a number of projects
- Integrated Elasticsearch as main search index to scale quickly growing project
- Introduced logstash and kibana for logs management
- Continuously performed refactoring to ensure code cleanliness and testability
- Worked hand to hand with product managers and design teams to provide all necessary technical support in defining product vision and strategy

AT Consulting, Expert developer April 2011 - January 2015

AT Consulting is one of the leading consulting and enterprise software developers in Russia. I worked as lead developer on several enterprise level, nationwide projects for government customers.

- Performed full-stack development of Java and Ruby on Rails applications
- Provided third level of support for partners and customers
- Created enterprise level integration layers using Java and ActiveMQ
- Helped operations team to troubleshoot production environment issues
- Coordinated distributed team of developers
- Closely interacted with system analysts and QA teams to define roadmap and vision of the projects and ensure high product quality

Education

Pskov State Polytechnical Institute

September 2006 - June 2011

Specialist degree in Computing machines, systems, complexes and networks.

Certificates

Functional Programming Principles in Scala Coursera, November 2012